lightspeedapp.com 2014-06-10

# Privacy Policy - LightSpeed POS

LightSpeed Retail Inc. (also referred to as “LightSpeed”, “us” or “we”) respects the privacy of every individual who visits this Website and is committed to the protection of their personal information. “Personal Information”, as used in this Privacy Policy, means information about an identifiable individual, but does not include the name, title or business address or telephone number of an employee of an organization.

This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) is incorporated into and forms part of the Terms of Use, which outlines the terms, and conditions you agree to when accessing and using the Website. By accessing and using the Website, you agree and consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information (information that can be used to identify you) as outlined in this Privacy Policy

### IP Protocol (IP) Addresses

When you access the Internet using your computer, your Internet service provider assigns you an IP Address. Generally, every time you connect to the Internet, your IP Address changes. In some circumstances (ie. with some broadband connections) your IP Address may not change in which case, it can be associated with your particular computer. Examples of the type of information that can be collected using your IP Address include your type of Internet Browser and the type of computer operating system you are using. LightSpeed, or its authorized agents, may use your IP Address to collect and report aggregate information on how the Website is being used and ways in which the Website can be improved.

### Web Log Information

Web log information is non-personal information that is collected by the computer that hosts the Website (the “Website Server”) when you visit the Website, including, but not limited to, the date and time you visited the Website, the type of Internet Browser you are using and the type of computer operating system you are using. Web log information may be collected and used by LightSpeed or its authorized agents in aggregate to assess how the Website is being used and how to improve the Website.

### Cookies

This Website uses a technology called “cookies”. A cookie is a token that a server gives to your browser when you access a website on the Internet. Cookies are capable of storing many types of data. Cookies help provide additional functionality to the Website or help us analyze the Website usage more accurately. For instance, our server may set a cookie that keeps you from having to enter a password more than once during a visit to the Website. In all cases in which cookies are used, we will not collect personally identifiable information without your explicit permission. With most Internet Browsers, you can erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block all cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Please refer to your Internet Browser’s instructions or help screen to learn more about these functions. You should be aware that operators of third party websites linked to the Website may also collect your personal information through the use of “cookies”. LightSpeed, its affiliates and any directors, officers, employees, agents, contractors, subcontractors or agents of the foregoing shall not be responsible for how such operators collect, use or disclose your personal information. You need to contact these operators directly for information on their data collection and distribution policies. Your linking to a third party website or webpage is entirely at your own risk and subject to the terms and conditions of such websites or webpages.

### Contacting LightSpeed By E-mail

Any communication, comments, ideas, concepts, know-how, techniques, material or other information (collectively, the “Communication”) that you voluntarily post or transmit to LightSpeed by e-mail is, and will be treated as, non-confidential and non-proprietary. By transmitting any Communication to LightSpeed by e-mail, you grant to LightSpeed and all of its affiliates, an unrestricted, irrevocable license to use, reproduce, display, modify, transmit, distribute, publish, broadcast or post your Communication for any purpose. However, we will not release your name in connection with such Communication unless: (a) you grant us permission to do so; (b) we first notify you that the Communication you submit to a particular part of the Website will be published or otherwise used with your name on it; or (c) we are required to do so by law.

### Policy Change

LightSpeed reserves the right, at its sole discretion, to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. Changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted on this page of the Website. Your continued access or use of the Website constitutes your acceptance of the Privacy Policy as revised. It is your responsibility to review the Privacy Policy frequently.

### Collection of Personal Information

LightSpeed only collects personal information from you when you voluntarily provide it to access or use this Website. If you refuse, are unwilling, or cannot accept the Terms of Use, which include this Privacy Policy, we may be unable to provide you with information or services from this Website. When accessing this Website as a non-registered or registered user, you may be asked to voluntarily provide certain personal information. You will be informed what information is required and what information is optional in order to access the Website. Only registered users are permitted to use interactive portions of this Website. If this Website contains interactive portions that you wish to participate in, you can become a registered user by completing and submitting the registration form available on the Website. Your personal information may be required to facilitate your use of and access to the interactive portions of the Website and LightSpeed’s ability to provide meaningful information to you. When you access the Website as a registered user, the personal information you provide during the registration process is used to partially complete certain interactive tools available only to registered users on the Website.

### Use of Personal Information

LightSpeed collects information, including personal information, that you voluntarily provide to us when you choose to participate in quizzes, polls, questionnaires or surveys on the Website, or when you use any interactive tools that may be available on this Website. Your personal information is stored on secure servers maintained by LightSpeed or by a third party on LightSpeed’s behalf as outlined below. Information collected on the Website, including personal information, may be stored on secure servers located outside of Canada.

LightSpeed may use your personal information (i) to respond to your questions or requests for additional information; (ii) to provide you with information that you have specifically requested, or that LightSpeed may ask you if you would like to receive (Example: e-mail refill reminders, e-newsletters); (iii) to personalize any interactive tools to better facilitate your use of the Website; (iv) to develop future e-newsletter topics for the Website; (v) to improve the Website; (vi) to understand how we can improve our products and services; and (vii) where you have submitted an online job application, for the purposes of recruitment and new hire administration, where applicable.

LightSpeed does not sell your personal information to third parties. LightSpeed will not disclose your personal information to any third party unless, (i) such disclosure is otherwise revealed to you when you submit your information; (ii) it is required by law or by an order of a competent court; (iii) if the rights or property of LightSpeed, its affiliates, Third Party Service Providers (as defined below), or users of the Website are in jeopardy; or (iv) if the safety of users of the Website or the general public are in jeopardy.

LightSpeed is careful to ensure that the information you voluntarily provide to the Website is secure as possible; however, you must be aware that transmissions over the Internet cannot be guaranteed to be completely secure. LightSpeed, its affiliates and any directors, officers, employees, agents, contractors, subcontractors or agents of the foregoing do not represent, warrant or guarantee that personal information will be protected against misuse, loss or modification, nor do such parties accept liability for the security of a user’s personal information submitted on or in connection with the Website.

### Disclosure of Personal Information to Third Party Service Providers

LightSpeed may have third party service providers perform services relating to the development, operation and maintenance of the Website or relating to other services noted above (“Third Party Service Providers”). These Third Party Service Providers may have access to your personal information, as is reasonably necessary, for the purpose of providing their services to LightSpeed.

### Access to Personal Information

If we hold personal information about you, you are able to access, change and update your personal information at any time. Requests for access to your personal information can be made in writing to: 

**Privacy Officer**  
LightSpeed Retail Inc.   
7049 St-Urbain Street   
Montréal (Québec)   
H2S 3H4   
Canada   

### Questions on Your Personal Information collected

All questions or concerns regarding our use of your Personal Information should be directed, in writing, to: 

**LightSpeed Retail Inc.**   
7049 St-Urbain Street   
Montréal (Québec)   
H2S 3H4   
Canada

[This Internet Privacy Policy is available in French by clicking [here](http://www.lightspeedretail.com/fr/privacy-policy/) / Cette politique relative à la protection des renseignements personnels sur internet est disponible en langue française en cliquant [ici](http://www.lightspeedretail.com/fr/privacy-policy/)]
